{
  "title": "5.7",
  "definitions": {
    "ENFEEBLE": {
      "word": "ENFEEBLE",
      "phonetic": "(en-fE'-bÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cause extreme weakness, make feeble </p><p>FEEBLE means <i class=“def-ital\">very weak, lacking strength.</i> The prefix <i class=“def-ital\">en-</i> means “to cause to be,” as in <i class=“def-ital\">enslave,</i> “to cause to be a slave.” So ENFEEBLE means “to cause to be FEEBLE.” </p><p>“The long illness ENFEEBLED him.” </p><p>“The animals were ENFEEBLED by lack of food.” </p><p>On the Pretest, many people think ENFEEBLE means <i class=“def-ital\">strengthen,</i> which is opposite in meaning. This may be due to a confusion of the prefix <i class=“def-ital\">en-</i> with <i class=“def-ital\">un-</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">in-,</i> both of which can mean <i class=“def-ital\">not.</i></p>"
    },
    "PROFOUND": {
      "word": "PROFOUND",
      "phonetic": "(prÔøΩfownd')",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">deep </p><p>The basic meaning of PROFOUND is <i class=“def-ital\">very deep.</i> The word is sometimes used about physical depth, but it is usually used about interests, ideas, feelings, and the like. PROFOUND often suggests depth of knowledge or wisdom. </p><p>“It was very difficult to awaken him from his PROFOUND sleep.” </p><p>“My father has a PROFOUND interest in painting.” </p><p>“The author showed a PROFOUND understanding of the way governments work.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROFUNDITY, n.</p>"
    },
    "CRESTFALLEN": {
      "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
      "phonetic": "(krest'-fol-ÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">discouraged, dejected, disappointed </p><p>A <i class=“def-ital\">crest</i> is the tuft of feathers on the top of a bird’s head. The basic meaning of CRESTFALLEN is “with the crest drooping or falling\"—that is, with the head hanging down. From this the word has come to mean “so disappointed, dejected, or discouraged that you want to hang your head.” </p><p>“Jim was CRESTFALLEN when he heard he hadn’t made the team.” </p><p>“Sally will be CRESTFALLEN if she doesn’t get a new bicycle for Christmas.” </p><p>“The boss told the CRESTFALLEN workers that he couldn’t afford to give them a raise.”</p>"
    },
    "EXALT": {
      "word": "EXALT",
      "phonetic": "(eg-zolt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to raise high, elevate, glorify </p><p>EXALT comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">high,</i> also the source for the word <i class=“def-ital\">altitude.</i> To EXALT someone is to make him higher, usually in rank, power, or dignity. </p><p>“They EXALTED her by calling her the greatest writer of our time.” </p><p>“In his EXALTED position he has little time for these little problems.” </p><p>The most common mistake on the Pretest is choosing <i class=“def-ital\">thrown out</i> as the meaning of EXALTED. This may be due to confusion about the <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> at the beginning of the word, which often means <i class=“def-ital\">out of.</i> Other forms of the word: EXALTATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "REGAL": {
      "word": "REGAL",
      "phonetic": "(rE'-gÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">royal, kingly </p><p> REGAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">king,</i> and means “belonging to or like a king.” The word often suggests the splendor and magnificence associated with a king. </p><p>“The king was dressed in all his REGAL splendor for this occasion.” </p><p>“He was disguised as a beggar, but his REGAL attitude gave him away.” </p><p>“They had a REGAL feast to celebrate their great victory.”</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "ALLURE": {
      "word": "ALLURE",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩIUr')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to attract, entice, charm </p><p>ALLURE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">lure,</i> and the two words have similar meanings. To ALLURE someone is to attract him with the offer of something valuable or pleasing. </p><p>“The salesman ALLURED us with tales of fabulous wealth if we bought this stock.” </p><p>“The hope of becoming a movie star ALLURES many young women to Hollywood.” </p><p>As a noun, ALLURE is this power of attraction, <i class=“def-ital\">charm.</i> </p><p>“The job offer lacked sufficient ALLURE to tempt her.” </p><p>“The city of Paris holds quite an ALLURE for many tourists.” Other forms of the word: ALLUREMENT, n. ALLURING, adj.</p>"
    },
    "AMICABLE": {
      "word": "AMICABLE",
      "phonetic": "(am'-i-k:)-bÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">friendly, peaceable, neighborly </p><p>AMICABLE is used about people’s actions or attitudes and means “showing good will,” <i class=“def-ital\">friendly.</i> AMICABLE is not a very strong word. It usually doesn’t suggest deep affection, but merely shows that people aren’t disposed to quarrel with one another. </p><p>“Both parties seemed eager for an AMICABLE settlement of their dispute.” </p><p>“The two countries maintained AMICABLE relations despite their disagreements.” </p><p>“We solved our differences AMICABLY and continued to work together.”</p>"
    },
    "GUTTURAL": {
      "word": "GUTTURAL",
      "phonetic": "(guht'-:)-rÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">of the throat. </p><p>Note the spelling. The word is spelled with <i class=“def-ital\">ur,</i> not <i class=“def-ital\">er,</i> in the middle. GUTTURAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">throat</i> and means “related to the throat.” The word is usually used about sounds that are produced in the throat and suggests a harsh, unpleasant quality. </p><p>“The sound of the <i class=“def-ital\">ch</i> in <i class=“def-ital\">acht,</i> the German word for ’eight,’ is a GUTTURAL sound\"—that is, it is formed in the throat, not the mouth.</p>"
    },
    "FOLLY": {
      "word": "FOLLY",
      "phonetic": "(fol'-E)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">foolishness, silliness </p><p>FOLLY means <i class=“def-ital\">foolishness, silliness, lack of wisdom.</i> The word often suggests that this foolishness might have bad consequences. </p><p>“Attempting to swim the Atlantic Ocean was an act of FOLLY.” </p><p>“It was FOLLY to ask the boss for a raise.” </p><p>FOLLY has been used about a particular event, place, or building. For example, when Secretary of State Seward advised President Lincoln to purchase Alaska, Alaska became known as “Seward’s FOLLY” because it was thought that nothing valuable existed there, and its purchase was just a waste of money. It is FOLLY to judge the value of a purchase too quickly.</p>"
    },
    "CONVEY": {
      "word": "CONVEY",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-vA')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to carry, deliver, transport; to communicate, make known </p><p>To CONVEY something is to carry it from one place to another. </p><p>“This pipe CONVEYS water from the well to the house.” </p><p>“Telegraph signals are CONVEYED from one town to another by wires.” </p><p>CONVEY is also used about ideas, information, and feelings and means to <i class=“def-ital\">make known,</i> either directly or indirectly. </p><p>“He CONVEYED his approval by nodding and smiling.” </p><p>“We wish to CONVEY our deepest sympathy to you on the death of your father.” </p><p>A CONVEYANCE is something that carries or transports, a <i class=“def-ital\">vehicle.</i> </p><p>“No public CONVEYANCES were operating during the snowstorm.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONVEYANCE, n.</p>"
    },
    "ANNUL": {
      "word": "ANNUL",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩnuhl')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cancel, nullify, make void </p><p>ANNUL comes from the Latin word <i class=“def-ital\">nullus,</i> which means “none.” <i class=“def-ital\">Nullus</i> is also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">null</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">nullify.</i> To ANNUL something is to make it cease to exist, to put an end to it. The word is most often used about legal agreements. To ANNUL a marriage is to declare that it is not legally valid. </p><p>“The judge ANNULLED the contract between the two companies.” </p><p>ANNUL is also sometimes used in other areas as well. </p><p>“Nothing could ANNUL the startling effect of her sudden appearance in the room.”</p>"
    },
    "PREMONITION": {
      "word": "PREMONITION",
      "phonetic": "(pre-m:)-ni'-shÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a forewarning, feeling of trouble coming, foreboding </p><p> A PREMONITION is a feeling that something, usually bad, is going to happen. There is no conscious reason for this feeling; it just seems to occur. </p><p>“She had a PREMONITION of the accident.” </p><p>“Sam didn’t pay attention to his PREMONITION that there was danger ahead.” </p><p>“He keeps having strange PREMONITIONS, but none of them seem to come true.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pre-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "FLAUNT": {
      "word": "FLAUNT",
      "phonetic": "(flont)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to show off, display, wave defiantly, attract attention to </p><p>To FLAUNT something is to show it off, to attract attention to it by displaying it or waving it around. </p><p>“He didn’t try to hide his bad habits. He FLAUNTED them in front of everyone.” </p><p>“Knowing they couldn’t catch him, the boy FLAUNTED the stolen wallet at them.” FLAUNT is very often confused with <i class=“def-ital\">flout,</i> a word which sounds almost the same but has a very different meaning. To <i class=“def-ital\">flout</i> something is to treat it with contempt, to scoff at it. </p><p>“He thinks we’re stupid; he’s always <i class=“def-ital\">flouting</i> our advice.” </p><p>To FLAUNT is to show off; to <i class=“def-ital\">flout</i> is to treat with contempt.</p>"
    },
    "SIMULATE": {
      "word": "SIMULATE",
      "phonetic": "(sim'-yU-IAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to pretend, pretend to be, imitate </p><p>SIMULATE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">similar.</i> To SIMULATE something is to take on its appearance, to pretend to be or have it. </p><p>“The fake fur SIMULATES the appearance and feel of real mink.” </p><p>“John SIMULATED lameness so that people would think he was injured.” </p><p>“Jane SIMULATED considerable reluctance to take the job, although she really was quite eager.” </p><p>“SIMULATED diamonds are much less valuable than real ones.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SIMULATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "ENCROACH": {
      "word": "ENCROACH",
      "phonetic": "(en-krOch')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to intrude, trespass, enter or take gradually  </p><p>To ENCROACH on or upon something is to advance farther than you are supposed to into it, to <i class=“def-ital\">trespass</i> on it. The word is used about trespassing on actual physical property, and also on things like rights and time. </p><p>“That new fence you built ENCROACHES on my property.” </p><p>“Your speech is too long. It will ENCROACH on my time to speak.” </p><p>ENCROACH is used especially when this trespassing happens gradually or secretly. </p><p>“Step by step the government started to ENCROACH on their rights.” </p><p>“As the years went by the sea ENCROACHED more and more on the land.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ENCROACHMENT, n. </p><p>Usage: ENCROACH is usually followed by on or upon.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "7",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "It ENFEEBLED them.",
          "answers": [
            "frightened",
            "weakened",
            "destroyed",
            "strengthened",
            "worried"
          ],
          "word": "ENFEEBLE",
          "correct": "weakened"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROFOUND understanding.",
          "answers": [
            "different",
            "some",
            "new",
            "deep",
            "little"
          ],
          "word": "PROFOUND",
          "correct": "deep"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Rather CRESTFALLEN.",
          "answers": [
            "suspicious",
            "angry",
            "discouraged",
            "ugly",
            "excited"
          ],
          "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
          "correct": "discouraged"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We shall be EXALTED.",
          "answers": [
            "let in",
            "impressed",
            "thrown out",
            "worn out",
            "raised high"
          ],
          "word": "EXALT",
          "correct": "raised high"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His REGAL manner.",
          "answers": [
            "vain",
            "polite",
            "royal",
            "usual",
            "poor"
          ],
          "word": "REGAL",
          "correct": "royal"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tried to ALLURE me.",
          "answers": [
            "capture",
            "attract",
            "order",
            "love",
            "frighten"
          ],
          "word": "ALLURE",
          "correct": "attract"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AMICABLE relations.",
          "answers": [
            "friendly",
            "changeable",
            "merry",
            "perfect",
            "hostile"
          ],
          "word": "AMICABLE",
          "correct": "friendly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GUTTURAL voice.",
          "answers": [
            "high",
            "sweet",
            "loud",
            "throaty",
            "frightening"
          ],
          "word": "GUTTURAL",
          "correct": "throaty"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "An act of FOLLY.",
          "answers": [
            "common sense",
            "bravery",
            "foolishness",
            "happiness",
            "love"
          ],
          "word": "FOLLY",
          "correct": "foolishness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Try to CONVEY it.",
          "answers": [
            "carry",
            "lift",
            "spot",
            "find",
            "get"
          ],
          "word": "CONVEY",
          "correct": "carry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ANNUL the treaty.",
          "answers": [
            "ignore",
            "accept",
            "renew",
            "delay",
            "cancel"
          ],
          "word": "ANNUL",
          "correct": "cancel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ignored his PREMONITION.",
          "answers": [
            "decision",
            "forewarning",
            "plan",
            "explanation",
            "advice"
          ],
          "word": "PREMONITION",
          "correct": "forewarning"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He FLAUNTED the thing.",
          "answers": [
            "ignored",
            "feared",
            "put away",
            "showed off",
            "respected"
          ],
          "word": "FLAUNT",
          "correct": "showed off"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SIMULATED knowledge.",
          "answers": [
            "improved",
            "acquired",
            "pretended",
            "useless",
            "genuine"
          ],
          "word": "SIMULATE",
          "correct": "pretended"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCROACH on the land.",
          "answers": [
            "hunt",
            "stay",
            "work",
            "live",
            "trespass"
          ],
          "word": "ENCROACH",
          "correct": "trespass"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can old age ENFEEBLE a person?",
          "word": "ENFEEBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an apprentice have a PROFOUND knowledge of his trade?",
          "word": "PROFOUND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people be CRESTFALLEN if they became rich?",
          "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you EXALT someone by insulting him?",
          "word": "EXALT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most people REGAL?",
          "word": "REGAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would the idea of catching a disease ALLURE many people?",
          "word": "ALLURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people be friendly during an AMICABLE discussion?",
          "word": "AMICABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a scream a GUTTURAL sound?",
          "word": "GUTTURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it FOLLY to try to pass another car on a curve?",
          "word": "FOLLY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a boat a CONVEYANCE?",
          "word": "CONVEY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a child ANNUL a marriage?",
          "word": "ANNUL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do PREMONITIONS always come true?",
          "word": "PREMONITION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a vain person FLAUNT his knowledge?",
          "word": "FLAUNT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can manufacturers make plastics to SIMULATE wood?",
          "word": "SIMULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people approve of someone who ENCROACHED upon their rights?",
          "word": "ENCROACH",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "His words of encouragement ENFEEBLED her to try again.",
          "word": "ENFEEBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He told us about his PROFOUND regret that he had never gone to college.",
          "word": "PROFOUND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The CRESTFALLEN players realized they just hadn't been good enough to beat the other team.",
          "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The emperor was friendly despite his EXALTED position.",
          "word": "EXALT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The wedding was a REGAL affair that would have pleased any king or queen.",
          "word": "REGAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ALLURE of gold has caused many men to become prospectors.",
          "word": "ALLURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They both decided they couldn't work together, so they parted AMICABLY.",
          "word": "AMICABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She gave a high, GUTTURAL giggle and said she was only kidding.",
          "word": "GUTTURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ed was FOLLY about model railroads. He would play with them all day.",
          "word": "FOLLY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It is hard to CONVEY to you how important I think this subject is.",
          "word": "CONVEY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The Supreme Court ANNULLED the agreement, stating that the president didn't have the power to enter into it.",
          "word": "ANNUL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had a PREMONITION afterwards that he had done poorly on the test.",
          "word": "PREMONITION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She got an A in every subject and FLAUNTED her report card in front of her classmates.",
          "word": "FLAUNT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The students SIMULATED an understanding of what the teacher was saying, but it really wasn't clear to them.",
          "word": "SIMULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The thieves ENCROACHED her pocketbook in broad daylight.",
          "word": "ENCROACH",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ENFEEBLE",
          "answers": [
            "weaken",
            "drain",
            "frighten"
          ],
          "word": "ENFEEBLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROFOUND",
          "answers": [
            "expensive",
            "deep",
            "wise"
          ],
          "word": "PROFOUND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CRESTFALLEN",
          "answers": [
            "unhappy",
            "dismayed",
            "unhealthy"
          ],
          "word": "CRESTFALLEN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXALT",
          "answers": [
            "begin",
            "glorify",
            "raise"
          ],
          "word": "EXALT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REGAL",
          "answers": [
            "imperial",
            "magnificent",
            "holy"
          ],
          "word": "REGAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ALLURE",
          "answers": [
            "fascinate",
            "improve",
            "enchant"
          ],
          "word": "ALLURE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AMICABLE",
          "answers": [
            "amiable",
            "pleasant",
            "restful"
          ],
          "word": "AMICABLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GUTTURAL",
          "answers": [
            "sharp",
            "throaty",
            "harsh"
          ],
          "word": "GUTTURAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FOLLY",
          "answers": [
            "absurdity",
            "unkindness",
            "silliness"
          ],
          "word": "FOLLY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONVEY",
          "answers": [
            "send",
            "tell",
            "delay"
          ],
          "word": "CONVEY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANNUL",
          "answers": [
            "nullify",
            "attack",
            "abolish"
          ],
          "word": "ANNUL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREMONITION",
          "answers": [
            "regret",
            "warning",
            "fear"
          ],
          "word": "PREMONITION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FLAUNT",
          "answers": [
            "boast",
            "show off",
            "pretend"
          ],
          "word": "FLAUNT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SIMULATE",
          "answers": [
            "copy",
            "increase",
            "imitate"
          ],
          "word": "SIMULATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCROACH",
          "answers": [
            "enter",
            "intrude",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "ENCROACH",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}